Burgis Pratt Starr Papers 2008.0063
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Burgis Pratt Starr Papers
undated, 1861-1887
2008.0063
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
2.0 Linear feet
The collection contains, among other personal papers, a diary documenting Mr. Starr's 1861-1862 travels through Europe and the Holy Land.
Starr, Burgis Pratt.
Biography
Burgis Pratt Starr was born on 13 Novemebr 1822 and died in Hartford, Connecticut, on 24 August 1883. He was married to Charlotte Gray Montague and resided at 27 Chapel Street, Hartford, CT. A published genealogist, Starr traveled extensively in Europe and the Holy Land in 1861-1862.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains travel diary and narrative, artifacts and photographs. Partial transcriptions of the diary and narrative were created by the donor and are available. Limited genealogical information is available in the repository.
Arrangement
Series I: Personal papers ( undated, 1861-1887 )
Series II: Travel documentation ( undated, 1861-1862 )
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Susan Johnson in June 2008.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the life and experiences of Connecticut residents. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Brainerd.; Pratt.; Starr, Burgis Pratt.; Starr.; Diaries.; Europe--Description and travel--19th century.; Palestine--Description and travel--19th century.; Photographs.; Sketches.
- Series I: Personal Papers, undated, 1862-1887
  - Clippings, undated, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, undated
    - Charlotte Montague Starr, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Burgis Pratt Starr, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bee Hive, Hartford, Connecticut, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Burgis Pratt Starr, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1882 (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1887 (Box 1)
- Series II: Travel documentation, undated, 1861-1862
  - Artifacts from the Holy Land, undated (Box 2)
  - Travel Diary, 1861-1862 (Box 1)
    General note
    [Four small books sewn together]
  - Travel Diary (photocopy, 2 binders), 1861-1862 (Box 1)
  - Travel diary (incomplete), 1861-1862 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Travel narrative, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 4)